TOMBS OF THE BLIND DEAD
Bet !
Hi !
Virginia !
- What are you doing in Lisbon ? - Business , my dear . You look gorgeous .
And you ? Some style you got . Actually , you 've always had it .
l remember when you taught me in school to paint my eyes with a burnt cork .
Oh , school days .
We 'd better not talk about that . It makes me feel old .
- Did you marry ? - No , I 'm still single . And you ?
I 'm going out with a guy , but it 's not serious .
You know , l did want to call you . But l haven 't had a day off until today .
- I 'm surprised . You 're in business ? - It 's interesting and somewhat bohemian .
l manufacture mannequins for showcases . l learned the trade back in Paris .
There are more opportunities here , so l set up my own shop .
- Where is it ? - Are you familiar ...
with the Montreal warehouse in the outskirts ?
- Next to the morgue ? - So what ? Until l find something better .
- Roger could help you . - Who 's Roger ?
That would be me .
Roger , this is my friend Bet . She makes puppets .
Mannequins , honey .
You never told me you had a friend like her .
- We met after - - - Don 't give out dates . Keep the mystery .
- Well , let 's celebrate. l met you today , too . - Where are you taking us ?
lf you 'd like , we could spend the weekend in the country .
- But Bet doesn 't like the country . - l guess you 'd rather be alone .
It 's not like that . Virginia and l are good friends . That 's all .
- Still , I 'd only get in the way . - You could bring a friend with you .
l don 't have any friends .
- But I 'll look for one . - They 'll come flying .
No . Men are really difficuIt these days .
- What time tomorrow ? - At 4 : 00 at the Abate Station .
I 'll be there . Bye .
The secret lies in pumping enough fuel . We won 't have any problems ...
- if the boiler 's full . - l see .
You 're taking charge , including checking the passengers for tickets .
- Yes , Father . - Load the coal . We 're leaving .
l already told you she would stand us up . It 'll be 5 : 00 soon .
She said she 'd come , so she 'll come . She 's just running late .
We 'd better board the train and find good seats .
Look . There she is .
- AII aboard ! - I 'm so sorry .
- Don 't worry . There 's a lot of traffic . - It 's not that .
My friend was coming , but he canceled at the last minute .
- His loss . Are we off ? - Not me. l just came to tell you .
You could have phoned the station .
l did , but a very nasty man told me that they can 't relay messages ...
to the passengers once they 're on the platform , so ...
please forgive me , and have fun . Bye .
Wait a second . You 're coming with us . Isn 't she , Virginia ?
Okay .
The landscape 's beautiful .
Come on . We 're already running late .
Get on . I 'll get the stuff .
- It looks like we 're the only ones here . - Not really .
It 's a great hotel . The best air you 'll ever breathe .
Speaking of air , have you got some cream ?
l don 't need any .
l do . You see , I 'm a city girl . l don 't want my nose to peel off .
- I 'll get it for you . - That 's okay .
l know exactly where it is .
- Too friendly for the first day . - What could happen tomorrow ?
I 'm choking here. l need some fresh air .
l think she 's upset .
l don 't see why .
It 's only natural . l think we 've been a bit inconsiderate .
l told you , there 's nothing between us .
And l really like you .
- It had to happen sooner or later . - Not with me . She 's my best friend .
She 's my friend , too . But what can you do ?
This is absurd . I 'm going to talk to her .
- Do you want me to - - - I 'd better go by myself .
You 're upset l came , aren 't you ?
You shouldn 't leave the compartment . This air 's bad for the skin .
- l mean the trip , that I 'm coming along . - Why should you care ?
Why do you talk like that ? l was your roommate in boarding school .
Have you forgotten , Virginia ? l was your confidante , your best friend .
I 'm sorry , Bet . l don 't know what 's wrong with me .
l don 't understand why l reacted that way .
Calm down . It doesn 't matter .
It was childish , because you 're still the same little girl .
The same girl who 'd come to my room trembling ...
who needed my trust , and answers to so many questions .
Please , stop . Don 't talk about that .
I 'll never forget you . And you 'll never forget me .
Remember what l taught you .
Your ticket , please .
- A man in the last car has it . - Okay . Enjoy your trip .
Excuse me .
- Where 's the next stop ? - We won 't stop until the end .
Can you stop for a moment , so that l can get off ?
That 's impossible . It 's against the rules . ln any case , where would you go out here ?
- Aren 't there any towns around here ? - Not for many miles .
- Thanks . - I 'm sorry .
- Virginia ! - Virginia , are you mad ?
Virginia !
- Come back ! - Come back , please !
What are you doing ?
- I 'm putting the brake on . - Don 't stop here .
Somebody pulled the alarm .
- It doesn 't matter . - Father , look .
Have fun .
She doesn 't know what she 's getting into .
- Father , what is it ? - Nothing . Put more coal in the boiler .
Is anyone there ?
Anyone ?
Is anybody here ?
l spoke to her maid . She said Virginia wasn 't back yet .
- Do you think she got lost ? - Breakfast , sir ?
No , thanks . Just the check .
There 's a town a few miles from here , isn 't there ?
No , sir . The mountain 's that way .
The Guadiana River 's that way , and the Spanish border .
- But we saw a town from the train . - You mean Berzano .
An abandoned medieval town . It 's not interesting .
A friend of ours spent the night there .
Oh , dear . Excuse me . I 'm so clumsy .
- What 's going on in Berzano ? - l don 't know anything , sir .
- There are rumors - - - What is it ?
We 're not allowed to talk about it . Old legends .
Modern folks don 't believe such tales .
Besides , you 'd be apprehensive . It 's not good for tourists .
- Go on . - Please. l can 't tell you anything more .
They 'll fire me .
Excuse me .
Something wrong ? Any complaints about our service ?
No , thanks . Could you help me get a horse ?
The hotel has an exercise ring you 'll love .
No , it 's not that . I 'd like to ride around the area .
Good idea . Our surroundings are beautiful .
- And another horse for me . - I 'd rather go alone .
- I 'm partly to blame . - We don 't know what we 'll find in Berzano .
That 's reason enough .
- Did you say Berzano ? You don 't mean - - - The town from the knights ' legend .
- My God ! We have to help her . - The farther we go , the better .
The police will take care of everything .
No signs of Virginia .
- This is amazing . - Yeah .
How are we getting back ?
- The train passes near here . - But it doesn 't stop here .
- Don 't worry . We 'll make it stop . - You think so ?
Why do you think the horses got scared ?
A snake . Who knows ?
Look . A medieval cemetery .
Do you sense something strange ?
It 's all strange .
l don 't know . Something in particular ?
Take a look at the crosses .
They 're not like the ones usually found in cemeteries .
They 're Egyptian crosses , exposed to flames .
ln the witch trials of the Middle Ages , it was said they were satanic .
They were used for satanic rites .
Let 's leave soon . These ruins look evil . l wouldn 't want to spend the night here .
We have time . We must find Virginia .
She couldn 't have stayed . She probably left after seeing all this .
Come on , she must be around somewhere .
Virginia !
Bet , look .
There 's no doubt she 's here .
Virginia !
That 's one of her shoes .
This is all very strange .
Virginia .
Virginia , are you there ?
Virginia , is that you ?
What are you doing here ?
A friend of ours spent the night in this house . We came looking for her .
- You mean Virginia White ? - Yes . How did you know ?
Police Officer Marcos , Inspector Oliveira .
- Did something happen to her ? - Where 's Virginia ?
How did you get here ?
We rented two horses from the hotel . They just escaped .
So , you 're Elizabeth Turner , and you 're Roger Whelan .
Yes , as a matter of fact .
You spent the night at the hotel and left at 1 1 : 00 this morning .
How do you know all that ?
Our police stations don 't have the latest technology , but we have a phone .
Please . Did anything serious happen to Virginia ?
Your friend has been murdered .
No .
It 's my fault .
But , what are you saying ?
How could we have imagined something like this ?
You have to identify her .
Come in .
It won 't be pleasant .
Come on . Get it over with .
Not her . We want to see the young woman who arrived this morning .
Yes , sir .
Here .
- Who would do such a thing ? - Well - -
- What do you think , Doctor ? - l haven 't performed the autopsy yet .
But l daresay it 's a strange case .
As if a pack of ferocious beasts had attached her .
She was probably tortured .
- None of her wounds are serious . - So what did she die from ?
- She bled to death . - Was she raped ?
It doesn 't look that way . The motive wasn 't sex , that 's for sure .
- Those bites came from a sadist . - Several sadists .
We were able differentiate between at least a dozen sets of teeth .
lf we weren 't in this century , I 'd say it was a ritual murder .
That 's not possible , Doctor .
There are no satanic sects or witches ' Sabbaths in our country .
Forget it . We 're in the 20th century .
What are you doing , Bet ?
That wig doesn 't go with a blue-eyed mannequin .
You 're right .
I 'm obsessed .
- It 's all been so horrible . - Forget your friend . Focus on your work .
That 's easy for you to say . lf you 'd seen her ... .
It would drive anyone crazy .
It 'd be good for you to take a trip , have a change of scenery .
l might as well . Once l find out what happened to Virginia .
It 's better to leave things as they are .
You know something about Berzano , don 't you ?
l don 't want to talk about it .
Open the door . That must be Roger .
Will you open it already ?
- Hi . Is Bet there ? - Yes . She 's expecting you .
- What 's that red light for ? - It 's from the skylight .
Illuminated signs are manufactured upstairs . They have to be tested .
- It must be pretty annoying . - Tell me about it .
- Hi , Bet . - Hello .
Of course , l had to drive around endlessly to find this place .
- What did you want to tell me ? - My assistant was born in Foz da Beira ...
a village 40 miles from Berzano .
What do you know about those ruins ?
l came here when l grew up .
You were there when you were young . What matters is what you heard .
l didn 't hear anything. l swear l didn 't .
You refuse to help us ? This is very important to us .
It 's a legend . They used to scare us with it when we misbehaved .
It 's probably nothing , but it still frightens me .
What 's the legend ?
Everybody used to talk about it . Berzano belonged to the knights .
These knights worshipped the devil and were excommunicated .
The village was abandoned . Nobody wanted to live there .
What does that have to do with our friend ?
The dead knights come out of their tombs to hunt .
- Hunt ? Hunt what ? - Human beings , to devour them like beasts .
- Still dressed like that ? - The autopsy took a long time .
You know how the police are .
- Did you find anything in particular ? - Besides the bites , nothing .
- Why did they do that to her ? - She was asking for it .
Going around flaunting herself . It 's as if they want to be bitten .
- And this one was really hot . - Yes .
What is it ? What 's wrong ? Are you scared ? Poor thing .
Relax .
And you thought I 'd forget about you ?
Not in your dreams . Let 's play a while .
I 'll show you .
WEEKDAYS 8 TO 7 - P NATIONAL MINISTRY OF EDUCATION
We 're gonna be late .
Professor Candal ?
Professor Candal .
Who are you ? What do you want ?
The library 's closed to the public . It 's always the same .
People are always arriving too late .
Excuse us , Professor . A friend of ours has been murdered .
What do l have to do with it ? Go to the police .
You 're the ultimate authority on medievalism .
And you 've studied the knights and their secret practices .
- l still don 't understand . - Our friend was tortured in Berzano .
Say that again ! You 're saying the knights have returned ?
- That 's great . - He 's crazy .
We 're not really sure .
And you want to find out .
Here they are .
The knights brought great treasures from the East ...
as well as witchcraft and occultism .
That 's why the Pope excommunicated them .
Their stories are fantastic and incredible .
No one has been able to uncover their great mysteries .
Do you think the village ... .
ln the 13th century , Berzano was the seat of one of their priories .
The Eastern knights were the absolute masters of this region .
Documents pertaining to their trial ...
claim that when they came back from the Holy Land ...
they brought the pharaohs ' ankh from Egypt ...
as a symbol of eternal life .
And they practiced satanic rites , seeking immortality .
Meanwhile , they oppressed their serfs and increased their assets ...
taking over cities and villages .
They were both hated and feared .
Let us offer our sacrifice to the darkness . We shall perform this rite ...
that the blood of the virgin may grant us a life beyond the bounds of the grave .
Their crimes were judged ...
and plenty of evidence and witnesses proved their guilt .
They were sentenced to death ...
and as a lesson , their bodies were hung for public display ...
until the crows ate their eyes .
- Can that be true ? - Absolutely .
The records of the trial leave no room for doubt .
And the connection to the current sacrifices ?
Are you suggesting a new sect has resumed the old rites ?
- No , it 's not that . - Then ?
- They 're the same . The old ones came back . - What nonsense is this ?
So much progress and science ...
and you fail to see what 's on the tip of your nose .
That 's right . Apart from many other secrets , the Eastern knights ...
solved the mystery of eternal life .
- But that 's impossible . - Do you remember the voodoo rites ?
Faust , and all those who make pacts with the evil spirit ...
do so with blood .
The knights performed human sacrifices ...
consummating the offering with a virgin 's blood .
Now they 've awakened from the beyond , and without eyes to see ...
they find their victims by the sounds they make ...
and continue to offer human sacrifices to their evil master .
That 's what many would have us believe .
Who 's there ?
It 's me , Professor . And l didn 't miss a single word of your fantastic tale .
Think what you like , but leave me alone . I 'm very busy .
One moment .
You have a son named Pedro , don 't you ?
Yes , l do .
- Why do you ask ? - Where 's Pedro now ?
l don 't know .
He left home two years ago .
l haven 't seen him since .
I 'll tell you , Professor .
He lives on a barge ...
along the Guadiana River ...
on the Spanish border .
He 's the leader of a smuggling ring .
l don 't want to hear any more . Stop .
Why are you telling us this , Inspector ?
That part of the river is about six miles from Berzano .
What are you trying to say ?
Those criminals are using the legend to their benefit .
And Virginia 's death ?
They 're spreading fear .
And keeping people away from the area where they commit their crimes .
That 's terrible .
Pedro would never kill anyone .
Was it necessary to be this cruel ?
Did you know they took your friend 's body and killed the morgue 's guard ?
Oh , my God . This is a nightmare .
Be very careful . Your workshop is very close to the morgue .
And although we have it under surveillance , we can never know for sure .
- Hello . - Nina ? It 's me , Bet . Don 't expect me .
l don 't know whether I 'll make it in tomorrow .
Send the two pending orders . Take note .
Ready ? Gonzaivo Warehouses , 17 Sinhai Street .
1 7 Sinhai Street . Got it .
Of course . I 'll ask them to sign the receipt .
Listen . Lock the door .
It doesn 't matter . Today 's a special day . Do it .
Listen to me . We 're in danger . I 'll explain it to you later .
That 's it . Bye , Nina . Bye .
Hello ! Please .
Hello .
- You 'll have to continue by foot . - l understand .
- You don 't want to get involved . - They 're dangerous .
- Should l go with you ? - Wait here .
lf I 'm not back in half an hour , call the police .
Okay .
I 'll wait half an hour . Not a minute longer .
- You know where l can find Pedro Candal ? - No , sir .
Go get him .
Pedro !
- Let that idiot yell . - Something 's up .
- Whatever . - It could be the police .
Pedro !
You 've pulled that trick on me twice .
They 'll be after me sooner or later .
All because of that cow , Amalia .
Why so difficult ? Tell me you 're going with her , and that 's it .
I 'll find a guy .
That 's all you think about .
What is it ? A visitor ?
Yes . A well-dressed guy is looking for you .
I 'll be right up .
What are you waiting for ? Do you like seeing him naked ?
I 'll be caught one day , but not by a woman .
At least I 'll know where you spend the night .
- Police ? - No , I 'm a decorator .
He 's harmless .
- What do you want . - What 's going on in Berzano ?
What do you think ? Nothing .
- It 's a ghost town . - However , they say - -
Do you believe such tales ?
No , but a friend of mine died there in a horrible way .
- What is it to me ? - The police suspect it was you .
- Why ? - To frighten people .
Oh , that .
We 've been in this area for three years . Nobody bothers us .
Our smuggling is modest , just to make a living .
- And now , do you really think that we ... . - No .
- How was she killed ? - Don 't go there now .
- What can l do for you ? - For me ? For yourself .
Fine . For both of us . What ?
- l want to know how my friend died . - How ?
- Come with me to Berzano . - l can 't . I 've got a job here .
You 're right to refuse . l wouldn 't do it if l were you .
- When are we leaving ? - Right away .
- We must spend the night in Berzano . - The night ? You mean sleep in Berzano ?
- Yes . Are you afraid ? - All right . Fine .
lf you go , I 'm going with you .
- What is it ? - Nothing .
- Are you armed ? - Yes .
Leave that for the ladies . Here .
- And you ? - I 'm fine with this .
A drink will perk you up .
Thanks .
Very chivalrous .
- A bit more and we run out . - Well , it 's mine , isn 't it ?
- I 'm taking a walk . - You want me to come along ?
- You think l need a bodyguard ? - l guess not .
- Still , if both of us - - - l told you I 'd come. l came .
But l don 't need your company .
Do whatever you want . Don 't worry about me .
Look at you .
Kind and soft like a porcupine .
Want to come along ?
Are you mad ? She 's so delicate .
With pleasure . Let 's go .
You both behave .
Some girl . She accepted so quickly .
She 's not fussy , is she ?
Big deal , they 're taking a walk together .
You want her to be faithful ?
There 's nothing between us .
Then forget it . You don 't know Pedro .
- And you don 't know Bet . - As if l care .
You have to accept things as they come .
And you 're not bad at all .
- Here . Have some . - What is it ?
Rum .
Have some more . Warm up . Enjoy the party .
- Where would you like to go ? - l don 't know . Not too far .
- Do you miss him ? - Who ?
- That guy . - He 's just a friend .
Well , let me take care of you . It 'll be okay .
Wow , not bad . And l thought you were prudish .
- Should we go outside ? - You want to see what they 're up to , right ?
- Do you always have to assume the worst ? - As you wish .
After all , when both agree , anywhere is fine .
It 's better if it stays with me .
l hope l won 't have to use it .
They 're hiding .
They must be around somewhere in the abbey .
What do you think they 'll do ?
l don 't know . Visit it .
You really think so ?
You 're very strange .
What are you looking at ?
l think I 'll have to disappoint you .
Why ?
l always feel apprehensive about men at the last minute .
So , you ...
never ... .
It 's a fear that was instilled in me as a child .
- I 'll help you change - - - You 'd better not try .
- This is a cemetery . - Quiet .
- No ! - What 's the difference ?
Let me go ! No !
No !
l suppose you won 't keep me walking all night ...
just because that whore went to get some .
- l told you she 's just a friend . - Sure . But you like her .
- Do you smoke ? - Okay .
But it would be better if it were a joint . We need to liven this up a bit .
- It 's Virginia 's . - Who ? The dead girl ?
But , how did she lose it ?
l knew a guy who liked to drink champagne from my oldest shoes .
It was the only thing that excited him .
- Let 's go . - Wait . What 's wrong with you ?
Who 's the joker ? Answer !
Whoever it is , come out ! Don 't make me come get you .
- What 's Pedro up to ? - It 's not him . The bells ringing on its own .
Go inside and lock the door .
- Don 't open it for anyone except for us . - Okay .
A little stroll through the ruins . Yeah , right . You wanted it that bad ?
- Who is it ? - It 's me , Roger . Open up . Open up !
- And Pedro ? - The knights killed him .
- The knights ? He can defend himself . - He 's in danger .
- What about us ? They 'll come after him . - Let me go . I 'm going to open it .
lf you open that door , I 'll kill you .
What 's going on in there ?
Open up , please . It 's me , Roger . Open up !
They 're getting close .
Open up !
Come here , bitch !
Freeze !
Whore !
No !
- Roger . - Don 't speak .
That 's the only way you 'll be safe .
Stop !
Father , look !
- Keep still . - Help me !
Help me , please .
Help me .
Hurry . Come on !
Hurry !
Run !
Let me help her .
Come on .
Up !
No !
Son !
Hey ! What are you doing in there ?
What is it ?
What happened ?
Please , don 't speak . You 'll be looked after .